<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Herbarium</string>

    <!--    Home Activity-->
    <string name="home_btn_tips"> \t <b>Tips on taking pictures</b> \n \t Tap here to learn more</string>
    <!--Home Activity -->

    <!--Akapulko-->

    <string name="titleDescription"><b>Description</b></string>
    <string name="titleBenefits"><b>Benefits and Treatment</b></string>
    <string name="titleUse"><b>Preparation and Use</b></string>
    <string name="titleMore"><b>More Information</b></string>


    <string name="title_activity_akapulko">Akapulko</string>
    <string name="headerAkapulko">
        <b>Plant Name:</b> Akapulko \n
        <b>Scientific Name:</b> Senna Alata \n
        <b>Family:</b> Leguminosae \n
    </string>

    <string name="titleDescriptionAkapulko"><b>Description</b></string>
    <string name="large_text1">Also known as ringworm bush, the scientific name of akapulko is Cassia alata or Senna alata. It is basically a shrub that is found all throughout the Philippines under different names, depending on the region. \n
    </string>

    <string name="titleBenefitsAkapulko"><b>Benefits and Treatment</b></string>
    <string name="large_text2">● <b>External Use:</b>
Treatment of skin diseases:
\n Tinea infections, insect bites, ringworms, eczema, scabies and itchiness. \n
● Mouthwash in stomatitis \n\n

● <b>Internal use:</b>
Expectorant for bronchitis and dyspnoea \n
● Alleviation of asthma symptoms \n
● Used as diuretic and purgative \n
● For cough and fever \n
● As a laxative to expel intestinal parasites and other stomach problems. \n\n

<b>Note:</b> A strong decoction of Akapulko leaves is an abortifacient. Pregnant women should not take the decoction of the leaves or any part of this plant. \n

    </string>

    <string name="titleUseAkapulko"><b>Preparation and Use:</b></string>
    <string name="large_text3">● For external use, pound the leaves of the Akapulko plant, squeeze the juice and apply on affected areas. \n\n

● As the expectorant for bronchitis and dyspnoea, drink decoction (soak and boil for 10 to 15 minutes) of Akapulko leaves. The same preparation may be used as a mouthwash, stringent, and wash for eczema. \n\n

● As laxative, cut the plant parts (roots, flowers, and the leaves) into a manageable size then prepare a decoction Note: The decoction loses its potency if not used for a long time. Dispose leftovers after one day. \n\n

● The pounded leaves of Akapulko have purgative functions, specifically against ringworms. \n\n

It should be noted that the pounded leaves of this plant may be applied thinly on the affected part twice a day. Marked improvement may be expected after two to three weeks of continuous application to the affected area(s) where the prepared Akapulko leaves were applied.

    </string>

    <string name="txt_title_more"><b>More Information:</b></string>
    <string name="large_text4"><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Senna_alata"> Wikipedia</a></string>
    <!--    Akapulko -->


    <string name="large_text">
        "Material is the metaphor.\n\n"

        "A material metaphor is the unifying theory of a rationalized space and a system of motion."
        "The material is grounded in tactile reality, inspired by the study of paper and ink, yet "
        "technologically advanced and open to imagination and magic.\n"
        "Surfaces and edges of the material provide visual cues that are grounded in reality. The "
        "use of familiar tactile attributes helps users quickly understand affordances. Yet the "
        "flexibility of the material creates new affordances that supercede those in the physical "
        "world, without breaking the rules of physics.\n"
        "The fundamentals of light, surface, and movement are key to conveying how objects move, "
        "interact, and exist in space and in relation to each other. Realistic lighting shows "
        "seams, divides space, and indicates moving parts.\n\n"

        "Bold, graphic, intentional.\n\n"

        "The foundational elements of print based design typography, grids, space, scale, color, "
        "and use of imagery guide visual treatments. These elements do far more than please the "
        "eye. They create hierarchy, meaning, and focus. Deliberate color choices, edge to edge "
        "imagery, large scale typography, and intentional white space create a bold and graphic "
        "interface that immerse the user in the experience.\n"
        "An emphasis on user actions makes core functionality immediately apparent and provides "
        "waypoints for the user.\n\n"

        "Motion provides meaning.\n\n"

        "Motion respects and reinforces the user as the prime mover. Primary user actions are "
        "inflection points that initiate motion, transforming the whole design.\n"
        "All action takes place in a single environment. Objects are presented to the user without "
        "breaking the continuity of experience even as they transform and reorganize.\n"
        "Motion is meaningful and appropriate, serving to focus attention and maintain continuity. "
        "Feedback is subtle yet clear. Transitions are efﬁcient yet coherent.\n\n"

        "3D world.\n\n"

        "The material environment is a 3D space, which means all objects have x, y, and z "
        "dimensions. The z-axis is perpendicularly aligned to the plane of the display, with the "
        "positive z-axis extending towards the viewer. Every sheet of material occupies a single "
        "position along the z-axis and has a standard 1dp thickness.\n"
        "On the web, the z-axis is used for layering and not for perspective. The 3D world is "
        "emulated by manipulating the y-axis.\n\n"

        "Light and shadow.\n\n"

        "Within the material environment, virtual lights illuminate the scene. Key lights create "
        "directional shadows, while ambient light creates soft shadows from all angles.\n"
        "Shadows in the material environment are cast by these two light sources. In Android "
        "development, shadows occur when light sources are blocked by sheets of material at "
        "various positions along the z-axis. On the web, shadows are depicted by manipulating the "
        "y-axis only. The following example shows the card with a height of 6dp.\n\n"

        "Resting elevation.\n\n"

        "All material objects, regardless of size, have a resting elevation, or default elevation "
        "that does not change. If an object changes elevation, it should return to its resting "
        "elevation as soon as possible.\n\n"

        "Component elevations.\n\n"

        "The resting elevation for a component type is consistent across apps (e.g., FAB elevation "
        "does not vary from 6dp in one app to 16dp in another app).\n"
        "Components may have different resting elevations across platforms, depending on the depth "
        "of the environment (e.g., TV has a greater depth than mobile or desktop).\n\n"

        "Responsive elevation and dynamic elevation offsets.\n\n"

        "Some component types have responsive elevation, meaning they change elevation in response "
        "to user input (e.g., normal, focused, and pressed) or system events. These elevation "
        "changes are consistently implemented using dynamic elevation offsets.\n"
        "Dynamic elevation offsets are the goal elevation that a component moves towards, relative "
        "to the component’s resting state. They ensure that elevation changes are consistent "
        "across actions and component types. For example, all components that lift on press have "
        "the same elevation change relative to their resting elevation.\n"
        "Once the input event is completed or cancelled, the component will return to its resting "
        "elevation.\n\n"

        "Avoiding elevation interference.\n\n"

        "Components with responsive elevations may encounter other components as they move between "
        "their resting elevations and dynamic elevation offsets. Because material cannot pass "
        "through other material, components avoid interfering with one another any number of ways, "
        "whether on a per component basis or using the entire app layout.\n"
        "On a component level, components can move or be removed before they cause interference. "
        "For example, a floating action button (FAB) can disappear or move off screen before a "
        "user picks up a card, or it can move if a snackbar appears.\n"
        "On the layout level, design your app layout to minimize opportunities for interference. "
        "For example, position the FAB to one side of stream of a cards so the FAB won’t interfere "
        "when a user tries to pick up one of cards.\n\n"
    </string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>


    <string name="title_activity_tosactivity">Terms Of Service \n</string>
    <string name="TOSp1">This End-User License Agreement (“EULA”) constitutes an agreement between you and Herbarium. (herein referred to as the “Owner”) with regard to the application for Mobile Phones (herein referred to as “Apps”). By installing the Software, you are agreeing to be bound by the terms of this license agreement.
Your use of the Apps (as specified below) is subject to the terms and conditions set forth in this EULA. If you do not accept the terms of this EULA, do not install or use the Software.
    </string>
    <string name="tosH1"><b>LICENSE\n</b></string>
    <string name="TOSp2">The Software is licensed, not sold. The Owner grants you a non-exclusive, non-transferable, non-sublicensable, limited right and license to use one copy of the Software for your personal non-commercial use on a single device. The rights granted herein are subject to your compliance with this EULA. The Software is being licensed to you and you hereby acknowledge that no title or ownership in the Software is being transferred or assigned and this EULA is not to be construed as a sale of any rights in the Software.\n
    </string>

    <string name="tosH2"><b>RESTRICTIONS OF USE\n</b></string>
    <string name="TOSp3">Unless the Owner has authorized you to distribute the Software, you shall not make or distribute copies of the Software or transfer the Software from one device to another. You shall not decompile, reverse engineer, disassemble, include in other software, or translate the Software, or use the Software for any commercial purposes. You shall not modify, alter, change or otherwise make any modification to the Software or create derivative works based upon the Software. You shall not rent, lease, resell, sub-license, assign, distribute or otherwise transfer the Software or this license. Any attempt to do so shall be void and of no effect.\n
    </string>

    <string name="tosH3"><b>COPYRIGHT\n</b></string>
    <string name="TOSp4">You acknowledge that no title to the intellectual property in the Software is transferred to you. You further acknowledge that title and full ownership rights to the Software, and you will not acquire any rights to the Software. You shall not remove or obscure the Owner’s copyright, trade mark or other proprietary notices from any of the materials contained in this package or downloaded together with the Software.\n
    </string>

    <string name="tosH4"><b>DISCLAIMER OF WARRANTY\n</b></string>
    <string name="TOSp5">The Software is provided “AS IS”, without warranty of any kind. We disclaim and make no express or implied warranties and specifically disclaim the warranties of merchantability, fitness for a particular purpose and non-infringement of third-party rights. The entire risk as to the quality and performance of the Software is with you. We do not warrant that the functions contained in the Software will meet your requirements or that the operation of the Software will be error-free.\n
    </string>

    <string name="tosH5"><b>LIMITATION OF LIABILITY\n</b></string>
    <string name="TOSp6">In no event will the Owner be liable for special, incidental or consequential damages resulting from possession, access, use or malfunction of the Software, including but not limited to damages to property, loss of goodwill, computer or mobile device malfunction and, to the extent permitted by law, damages for personal injuries, property damage, lost profits or punitive damages from any causes of action arising out of or related to this EULA or the Software, whether arising in tort (including negligence), contract, strict liability or otherwise and whether or not the Owner has been advised of the possibility of such damages.
Because some states/countries do not allow certain limitations of liability, this limitation of liability shall apply to the fullest extent permitted by law in the applicable jurisdiction. This limitation of liability shall not be applied solely to the extent that any specific provision of this limitation of liability is prohibited by any federal, state, or municipal law, which cannot be pre-empted. This EULA gives you specific legal rights, and you may have other rights that vary from jurisdiction to jurisdiction. In no event shall the Owner’s liability for all damages (except as required by applicable law) exceed the actual price paid by you for use of the Software.\n
    </string>


    <!--Tsaang Gubat-->

    <string name="title_activity_tsaang_gubat">Tsaang gubat</string>
    <string name="headerTsaangGubat">
        <b>Plant Name:</b> Tsaang Gubbbat \n
        <b>Scientific Name:</b> Carmona retusa \n
        <b>Family:</b> Boraginaceae \n
    </string>

    <string name="DescriptionTG">Also known as ringworm bush, the scientific name of akapulko is Cassia alata or Senna alata. It is basically a shrub that is found all throughout the Philippines under different names, depending on the region. \n
    </string>

    <string name="BenefitsTG"> ● Stomach pains \n\n
● Gastroenteritis \n\n
● Intestinal motility \n\n
● Dysentery \n\n
● Diarrhea or Loose Bowel Movement (LBM) \n\n
● Mouth gargle \n\n
● Body cleanser/wash \n\n


    </string>

    <string name="useTG">● Thoroughly wash the leaves of tsaang gubat in running water. Chop to a desirable size and boil 1 cup of chopped leaves in 2 cups of water. Boil in low heat for 15 to 20 minutes and drain. \n\n
● Take a cupful every 4 hours for diarrhea, gastroenteritis and stomach pains.\n\n
● Gargle for stronger teeth and prevent cavities.\n\n
● Drink as tea daily for general good health.\n\n


    </string>


    <string name="moreTG"><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ehretia_microphylla"> Wikipedia</a></string>
    <!--    Tsaang Gubat -->


    <!--Oregano-->
    <string name="title_activity_oregano">Oregano</string>

    <string name="headerOregano">
        <b>Plant Name:</b> Oregano \n
        <b>Scientific Name:</b>  Origanum vulgare \n
        <b>Family:</b> Mint family (Lamiaceae) \n
    </string>

    <string name="descriptionOregano">Oregano is also known as Wild Marjoram, Mountain Mint, Origanum, Wintersweet and Winter Marjoram. This erectly spreading plant has strong aromatic characteristics, with leaves and stems that are fleshy. The leaves of oregano are heart-shaped, with toothed edges, and which, grow up to 9 meters in length. In other countries, the plant is primarily used as a culinary ingredient. However, in countries like the Philippines, Oregano is a known herbal medicine for its strong anti-oxidant properties. \n
    </string>

    <string name="benefitsOregano"> ● Good for cough and cold relief \n\n
● Helps prevent degenerative arthritis \n\n
● Has Anti-aging properties \n\n
● Helps relieve rheumatism and osteoarthritis \n\n
● Bronchitis herbal remedy \n\n
● Ease asthma attacks \n\n
● Relieves upset stomach \n\n
● Treatment of urinary tract problems \n\n
● Relief for dyspepsia or indigestion \n\n
● Healing wounds, insect bites and stings \n\n
● Cure for sore throat \n\n
● Avoid infections caused by childbirth by taking decoctions of the leaves by the recent mother. \n\n
● For general good health \n\n


    </string>

    <string name="useOregano">● Boil one cup of fresh leaves in 3 cups of water for 10 to 15 minutes. Drink half a cup 3 times a day for common colds. \n\n
● For a concentrate, juice the oregano leaves and take 1 tablespoon every hour to relieve chronic coughs, rheumatism, bronchitis, asthma, and dyspepsia. \n\n
● For Insect bites, wounds and stings, apply the leaves as a poultice directly on the afflicted area. \n\n
● For sore throat, boil 2 tablespoonfuls of dried oregano leaves in a pint of water, take 2 hours before or after meals. \n\n
● To prevent degenerative arthritis and for general good health drink oregano decoction daily. \n\n

    </string>

    <string name="moreOregano"><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Oregano"> Wikipedia</a></string>

    <!--  Oregano -->


    <!--Malunggay-->
    <string name="title_activity_malunggay">Malunggay</string>

    <string name="headerMalunggay">
        <b>Plant Name:</b> Malunggay \n
        <b>Scientific Name:</b>  Moringa oleifera \n
        <b>Family:</b> Moringaceae  \n
    </string>

    <string name="descriptionMalunggay">The malunggay plant is known to different parts of the world under various names including, but not limited to, horseradish tree, drumstick tree, and dool in some regions. It is one of the more popular and publicized plants that is acknowledged to have nutritional, as well as, medicinal value. It is rich in vitamins A, B and C, minerals such as iron and amino acids. Fortunately, the plant is easily accessible as it can be found not only as part of the wild life, but also in the backyards of many Filipino homes. \n
    </string>

    <string name="benefitsMalunggay">The leaves of this plant proved to be a good source of calcium, iron, ascorbic acid and phosphorus. Its other parts such as the seeds, the young pods, and the flowers have been established to benefit individuals as far as antioxidant, anti-diabetic, circulatory stimulations, and such other activities that are most beneficial to mankind, are concerned. There have been claims that malunggay can be used to lower blood pressure, aid in pains caused by rheumatism, headaches and migraines, as well as its being an anti-tumor plant. Malunggay is also used for purgative and anti-fungal purposes, as well. The leaves can be applied to minor wounds for faster healing. It can also relieve indigestion by drinking a concoction of its leaves or mixed with food. All these prove the claim that this plant is indeed multi-purpose. \n
    </string>

    <string name="useMalunggay">To harness the benefits of dried malunggay leaves, you must first dry them. To do so, collect malunggay stems. Wash your collected Moringa with baking soda solution. To create the solution, mix 2 tablespoons of baking soda with 1 liter of water. After washing the malunggay, air-dry it. Do not place it under direct sunlight. You can even dry it indoors for 2 to 3 days. \n\n
        Once the malunggay is completely dry, the leaves will fall off. To hasten the process, shake the stem and collect the leaves. Now that you have the dried leaves, crush them with your clean hands, and store them in an airtight container. \n\n
        Use the dried leaves by mixing it into your dough for bread and noodles. You can also add it in hot water to enjoy instant tea, or you can simply sprinkle it on your dishes. \n
    </string>

    <string name="moreMalunggay"><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moringa_oleifera"> Wikipedia</a></string>

    <!--Malunggay-->

    <!--  Niyog-niyogan -->

    <string name="title_activity_niyog_niyogan">Niyog-Niyogan</string>

    <string name="headerNiyog_Niyogan">
        <b>Plant Name:</b> Niyog-Niyogan \n
        <b>Scientific Name:</b> Combretum indicum \n
        <b>Family:</b> Combretaceae  \n
    </string>

    <string name="descriptionNiyog_Niyogan">Niyog-niyogan or Rangoon Creeper is an excellent vine for outdoor gardens. This ligneous plant, scientifically called Quisqualis indica L. It is also known as Burma or Rangoon Creeper, Liane Vermifuge and Chinese honeysuckle. Niyog-niyogan is perfect for covered walkways as it grows at least 2.5m long and reaches up to 8m long when it matures. This active climber, which belongs to the combretaceae family, grows best in tropical areas and demands constant sunlight. Perhaps due to its tropical characterization that it is found in primary and secondary forests of countries like Africa, China, Taiwan, Malaysia, Philippines, Vietnam, Papua New Guinea and other Asian regions.\n
    </string>

    <string name="benefitsNiyog_Niyogan">Almost all of its parts are used individually, or mixed with other ingredients, as remedy to different ailments. In the Philippines, these are taken to rid people of parasitic worms. Some also use these to help alleviate coughs and diarrhea. Medical experts, advice patients to consult their doctors as improper dosing may cause hiccups. Niyog-niyogan’s leaves are used to cure body pains by placing them on specific problematic areas of the body. Compound decoctions of the leaves of niyog-niyogan are used in India to alleviate flatulence. \n
    </string>

    <string name="useNiyog_Niyogan">●Get the seed from the parent plant and its withered fruit \n\n
● Eat it; chew it well and follow with drinking a half full or 1 glass of water. \n\n
● Dosage of seeds to eat based on patient’s age: 4-5 seeds (4-6 years old); 6-7 seeds (7-12 years old); 8-10 seeds (13 years old and above) \n\n
● If there is still no worm that came out during a bowel movement, you may use the same dosage after 1 week. \n\n
● Possible side effects especially after overeating seeds: nausea, hiccups, stomach ache, or diarrhea. Do not eat more than the recommended amount of seeds.\n
    </string>

    <string name="moreNiyog_Niyogan"><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Combretum_indicum"> Wikipedia</a></string>

    <!--  Niyog-niyogan -->

    <!-- Bayabas -->

    <string name="title_activity_bayabas">Bayabas</string>

    <string name="headerBayabas">
        <b>Plant Name:</b> Bayabas \n
        <b>Scientific Name:</b> Psidium guajava \n
        <b>Family:</b> Myrtaceae \n
    </string>

    <string name="descriptionBayabas">Bayabas or guava is a tropical plant, which is locally known for its edible fruit. In the backyards of Filipino homes in the country, this plant is commonly seen, and grown because of its many uses as fruit and as traditional remedy to treat various ailments. As shown by many research studies, almost all of the parts of this plant have medicinal qualities and value, and thus, making it one of the most popular therapeutic plants in the Philippines. Bayabas is a small tree that can grow up to 3 meters tall with greenish-brownish smooth bark. The round globular bayabas fruit starts as a flower and is usually harvested and eaten while still green. The fruit turns yellowish-green and soft when ripe.\n
    </string>

    <string name="benefitsBayabas">● Antiseptic, astringent and anthelmintic \n\n
● Kills bacteria, fungi and ameba \n\n
● Used to treat diarrhea, nose bleeding \n\n
● For Hypertension, diabetes and Asthma \n\n
● Promotes menstruation \n\n
● Prevents pimples, blackheads and skin blemishes. \n\n

The fresh leaves are used to facilitate the healing of wounds and cuts. A decoction (boiling in water) or infusion of fresh leaves can be used for wound cleaning to prevent infection. Bayabas is also effective for toothaches. Note: Bayabas can cause constipation when consumed in excess. \n

    </string>

    <string name="useBayabas">● Boil one cup of Bayabas leaves in three cups of water for 8 to 10 minutes. Let cool. \n\n
● Use decoction as mouthwash, gargle. \n\n
● Use as wound disinfectant - wash affected areas with the decoction of leaves 2 to 3 times a day. Fresh leaves may be applied to the wound directly for faster healing. \n\n
● For toothaches, chew the leaves in your mouth. \n\n
● For diarrhea, boil the chopped leaves for 15 minutes in water, and strain. Let cool, and drink a cup every three to four hours. \n\n
● To stop nosebleed, densely roll Bayabas leaves, then place in the nostril cavities. \n\n
● For pimples and other skin disorders, apply to the skin with a cotton ball. \n
    </string>

    <string name="moreBayabas"><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Psidium_guajava"> Wikipedia</a></string>

    <!--  Bayabas -->

    <!-- Ampalaya -->

    <string name="title_activity_ampalaya">Ampalaya</string>

    <string name="headerAmpalaya">
        <b>Plant Name:</b> Ampalaya \n
        <b>Scientific Name:</b> Momordica charantia \n
        <b>Family:</b> Cucurbitaceae \n
    </string>

    <string name="descriptionAmpalaya">Ampalaya (Bitter Melon) is a climbing vine and the tendrils of which grow up to 20 centimeters long. This herbal plant belongs to the family of Cucurbitaceae, and it is a tropical as well as a subtropical vine. Ampalaya leaves are heart-shaped, which are 5 to 10 centimeters in diameter. The fruits of the ampalaya vine are fleshy green with pointed ends at length. It can never be mistaken for any other variety because its ribbed and wrinkled surface had always been an ampalaya distinct physical structure. The bitter taste of the ampalaya fruit had also been the distinguishing factor from the rest of the fruits with medicinal value, and this is due to the presence of a substance known as momordicin.\n
    </string>

    <string name="benefitsAmpalaya">● Good for rheumatism and gout \n
● And diseases of the spleen and liver \n
● Aids in lowering blood sugar levels \n
● Helps in lowering blood pressure \n
● Relieves headaches \n
● Disinfects and heals wounds and burns \n
● Can be used as a cough and fever remedy \n
● Treatment of intestinal worms, diarrhea \n
● Helps prevent some types of cancer \n
● Enhances immune system to fight infection \n
● For treatment of hemorrhoids \n
● Is an antioxidant and parasiticide \n
● Is antibacterial and antipyretic \n


    </string>

    <string name="useAmpalaya"> ● Consult a health center for a formal diagnosis and medical advice for diabetes, including the use of ampalaya leaves (Makiling variety) to help control blood sugar levels \n\n
● Health care professionals may advise patients to eat 1 cup of ampalaya leaves twice a day (as salad or as an ingredient in meals) \n\n
● Health care professionals may also advise patients to boil 2 cups of sprouts in 2 glasses of water until only half of the water is left (around 15 minutes of boiling), and to drink ⅓ of the boiled water (decoction) thrice a day (30 minutes before meals) \n\n
● For coughs, fever, worms, diarrhea, diabetes, juice Ampalaya leaves and drink a spoonful daily. \n\n
● For other ailments, the fruit and leaves can both be juiced and taken orally. \n\n
● For headaches wounds, burns and skin diseases, apply warmed leaves to afflicted area. \n\n
● Powdered leaves, and the root decoction, may be used as stringent and applied to treat hemorrhoids. \n\n
● Internal parasites are proven to be expelled when the ampalaya juice, made from its leaves, is extracted. The ampalaya juice, and grounded seeds is to be taken one spoonful thrice a day, which also treats diarrhea, dysentery, and chronic colitis. \n

    </string>

    <string name="moreAmpalaya"><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Momordica_charantia"> Wikipedia</a></string>

    <!--  Ampalaya -->

    <!-- Balbas-pusa -->
    <string name="title_activity_balbas_pusa">Balbas-pusa</string>

    <string name="headerBalbasPusa">
        <b>Plant Name:</b> Balbas-pusa \n
        <b>Scientific Name:</b> Orthosiphon aristatus \n
        <b>Family:</b> Mint family (Lamiaceae)  \n
    </string>

    <string name="descriptionBalbasPusa"> It is commonly referred to as Java tea, is a tropical perennial plant that has a peculiar long white or purple, two-lipped flowers with protruding stamens, that give the flower its characteristic cat’s whiskers appearance. Balbas pusa has taken its niche in the folkloric herbal medicine believed to have benefits for kidney and bladder health. \n
    </string>

    <string name="benefitsBalbasPusa">●	Antioxidant \n
●	Anti-inflammatory \n
●	Antihypertensive \n
●	Antidiabetic \n
●	Antirheumatic \n
●	Anti-gout \n
●	Diuretic \n
●	Neuroprotective, hepatoprotective and nephroprotective \n
●	Anti-neuropathic/Anti-urolithiatic \n
●	Anti-allergy \n
●	Asthma and cough remedy \n
●	Antibacterial \n
●	Antifungal \n
●	Antispasmodic \n
●	Assists in weight loss \n
●	Treats skin disorders/Maintains healthy skin \n
●	Stress relief \n

    </string>

    <string name="useBalbasPusa">●	Wash fresh Balbas pusa or cat\'s whisker leaves \n
●	Chop then add in 4 cups of water for every 1 cup  \n
●	Let it boil for 10 to 15 minutes   \n
●	Let it steep then strain. \n
●	Drink half cup of balbas pusa tea also known as java tea three times a day.  \n
●	Balbas pusa tea concoction can be stored in a suitable glass container for later consumption.  \n

    </string>

    <string name="moreBalbasPusa"><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Orthosiphon_aristatus"> Wikipedia</a></string>

    <!--  Balbas-pusa -->

    <!-- Lagundi -->
    <string name="title_activity_lagundi">Lagundi</string>

    <string name="headerLagundi">
        <b>Plant Name:</b> Lagundi \n
        <b>Scientific Name:</b> Vitex negundo \n
        <b>Family:</b> Mint family (Lamiaceae)  \n
    </string>

    <string name="descriptionLagundi"> It is one of the ten herbal medicines endorsed by the Philippine Department of Health as an effective herbal medicine with proven therapeutic value. Commonly known in the Ilocos region as dangla, lagundi has been clinically tested to be effective in the treatment of colds, flu, fever, bronchial asthma, chronic bronchitis, and pharyngitis. \n
    </string>

    <string name="benefitsLagundi">● Relief of asthma and pharyngitis \n\n
● Recommended relief of rheumatism, dyspepsia, boils, diarrhea \n\n
● Treatment of cough, colds, fever and flu and other bronchopulmonary disorders \n\n
● Alleviate symptoms of Chickenpox \n\n
● Removal of worms, and boils \n

    </string>

    <string name="useLagundi">● Boil half cup of chopped fresh or dried leaves in 2 cups of water for 10 to 15 minutes. Drink half a cup three times a day. \n\n
● For skin diseases or disorders, apply the decoction of leaves and roots directly on skin. \n\n
● The root is specially good for treating dyspepsia, worms, boils, colic and rheumatism. \n\n
A decoction (boiling in water) of the roots and leaves of Lagundi are applied to wounds, and used as aromatic baths for skin diseases. Boiled seeds are eaten in order to prevent the spreading of toxins and venom from bites of poisonous animals. Juice extracted from the flowers of the Lagundi plant is taken in as an aid for disorders like fever, diarrhea, liver disorders, and even cholera. While a decoction of the plant leaves is suggested to be taken by individuals to help increase the flow and production of milk, as well as to induce menstruation. \n


    </string>

    <string name="moreLagundi"><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vitex_negundo"> Wikipedia</a></string>

    <!--  Lagundi -->


    <!-- Sambong -->
    <string name="title_activity_sambong">Sambong</string>

    <string name="headerSambong">
        <b>Plant Name:</b> Sambong \n
        <b>Scientific Name:</b> Blumea balsamifera \n
        <b>Family:</b> Compositae \n
    </string>

    <string name="descriptionSambong"> Sambong is one herbal medicine (of ten) approved by the Philippine Department of Health (DOH) as an alternative medicine in treating particular disorders. It is known in the Visayas as bukadkad and as subsob in Ilocos. The plant is a strongly aromatic herb that grows tall and erect. Its height ranges from 1.5 to 3 meters, with stems that grow for up to 2.5 centimeters. It is an anti-urolithiasis and works as a diuretic. \n
    </string>

    <string name="benefitsSambong"> ● Good as a diuretic agent \n\n
● Effective in the dissolving kidney stones \n\n
● Aids in treating hypertension and rheumatism \n\n
● Treatment of colds, cough and fever \n\n
● Anti-diarrheic properties \n\n
● Anti-gastralgic properties \n\n
● Helps remove worms, boils \n\n
● Relief of stomach pains \n\n
● Treats dysentery, sore throat \n\n
● Decoction mixed in bathing water for new mothers. \n

    </string>

    <string name="useSambong"> ● A decoction (boil in water) of Sambong leaves is like tea and you drink a glass 3 or 4 times a day. \n\n
● The leaves can also be crushed or pounded and mixed with coconut oil. \n\n
● For headaches, apply crushed and pounded leaves on the forehead and temples. \n\n
● Decoction of leaves is used as a sponge bath. \n\n
● Decoction of the roots, on the other hand, is to be taken in as a cure for fever. \n

    </string>

    <string name="moreSambong"><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blumea_balsamifera"> Wikipedia</a></string>

    <!--  Sambong -->

    <!-- Ulasimang bato -->
    <string name="title_activity_ulasimang_bato">Ulasimang Bato</string>

    <string name="headerUlasimangBato">
        <b>Plant Name:</b> Ulasimang Bato \n
        <b>Scientific Name:</b> Peperomia pellucida Linn. \n
        <b>Family:</b> Piperaceae \n
    </string>

    <string name="descriptionUlasimangBato"> Ulasimang bato is an herbal medicine also known as Pansit-pansitan, olasiman-ihalas and tangon-tangon in the Philippines. It is a small herb that grows from 1 to 1 1/2 feet. It can be found wild on lightly shaded and damp areas such as nooks, walls, yards and even roofs. Pansit-pansitan has heart shaped leaves, succulent stems with tiny flowers on a spike. When matured, the small fruits bear one seed which falls off the ground and propagates. \n
    </string>

    <string name="benefitsUlasimangBato"> ● Antibacterial \n\n
●	Anticancer, antioxidant \n\n
●	Depressant \n\n
●	Anti-gout \n

    </string>

    <string name="useUlasimangBato">  Tips on how to control uric acid \n\n
●	Consult a doctor at a health center to diagnose your symptoms, and to know the medicine for gout including how to use pansit pansitan to help in controlling your uric acid levels. \n\n
●	The doctor may advise to eat 1 cup (not crammed) of leafy tops of pansit-pansitan thrice during the day (as a salad). Also, the doctor may advise to boil 1 1/2 glasses (or 3 cups), not crammed, of pansit-pansitan in 2 glasses of water until the water reduces to half (boil for around 15 minutes), and drink the 1/3 glass of boiled water thrice in the day after eating. \n

    </string>

    <string name="moreUlasimangBato"><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peperomia_pellucida"> Wikipedia</a></string>

    <!--  Ulasimang bato -->

    <!-- Yerba -->
    <string name="title_activity_yerba">Yerba</string>

    <string name="headerYerba">
        <b>Plant Name:</b> Yerba \n
        <b>Scientific Name:</b>Clinopodium douglasii \n
        <b>Family:</b> Mint family (Lamiaceae) \n
    </string>

    <string name="descriptionYerba"> It is an aromatic plant used as herbal medicine worldwide. This perennial plant’s growth ranges from 0.6 meters to 1 meter. It has elongated leaves and in summers, it bears small whitish or purplish flowers. Such flowers possess both male and female organs that allow it to be pollinated by bees and animals of the same nature. The word Yerba Buena is Spanish for "good herb" and was the former name of the California city of San Francisco. \n
    </string>

    <string name="benefitsYerba"> ● Arthritis \n\n
● Headaches \n\n
● Tooth aches \n\n
● Mouth wash \n\n
● Relief of intestinal gas \n\n
● Stomach aches \n\n
● Indigestion \n\n
● Drink tea for general good health. \n


    </string>

    <string name="useYerba">  <b>For toothaches </b>
●	Boil the grinded and freshly picked yerba buena leaves in a pot filled with 2 glasses of water until the pot is only left with half filled of water. Keep the lid off the pot after bringing it to a boil. \n\n
●	 Let it cool completely and then strain it. \n\n
●	 Divide it into 2 portions. Drink 1 portion, and drink another 1 portion after 3-4 hours if the pain still persists. \n\n
●	 Dosage of minced sambong leaves based on patient’s age: 3 tablespoons (7-12 years old); 6 tablespoons (13 years old and above) \n\n
●	 Visit a health center and consult about your illness if the toothache still persists. \n\n

<b> Headache </b> \n\n
●	 Compress or crush freshly picked leaves and use the extract in massaging the forehead and top of head. \n\n
●	Consult with a health center if the headache still persists. \n

    </string>

    <string name="moreYerba"><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clinopodium_douglasii"> Wikipedia</a></string>

    <!--  Yerba -->

    <!--    Guide -->
    <string name="title_activity_guide">Guide</string>

    <string name="guideHeader"><b>How to use Herbarium:\n</b>
    To identify a Medicinal plant, simply take a picture of the plant leaf or select a plant leaf picture from your "Gallery" and Herbarium will identify it instantly! \n\n

    <b>Tips on taking pictures:</b>\n
    A clear shot of plants leaf with proper angle and distance will help Herbarium identify Medicinal plants more accurately.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="step1"> <b>1. Single leaf only\n</b>
    DO NOT put so much object in the photo, you only need one leaf.
    </string>

    <string name="step2"> <b>2. Bright and clear\n</b>
   	Make sure the picture you take or select in the gallery is Bright and Clear enough to identify. You\'ll have better result from that.
    </string>

    <string name="step3"> <b>3. In the middle rule\n</b>
   Put your leaf into the center of the frame
    </string>

    <string name="step4"> <b>4. Stay Original\n</b>
   DO NOT edit or adjust any effect on your photo, you only need the original one.
    </string>
    <string name="title_activity_plants">PlantsActivity</string>


    <!--    Guide -->

</resources>